Andrew W Surber

Creative problem solver with 15+ years experience in professional IT environments. Multiple skillset background with focal points on Identity Access Management (IAM), Privileged Access Management (PAM), Automation (Python, Powershell) and Event Management. Seeking opportunities to utilize technology to find solutions for existing and future challenges.

Contacts

PO Box 160601, Sacramento, CA 95816

<u>LinkedIn</u> [https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-w-surber/]

GitHub [https://github.com/awbored]

Summary of Qualifications

- 5+ years working in Sailpoint Identity IQ (IAM) & CyberArk (PAM)
- 7+ years working in Active Directory (LDAP)
- 2 years working in Ansible Automation (Why repeat tasks when we can automate)
- Maintained quick turnaround of projects and tasks

Contents

- Andrew W Surber
 - Contacts
 - Summary of Qualifications
- Technical Skills
 - Platforms
 - <u>Languages</u>

- Databases
- Software
- Concepts
- Professional Experience
 - Sutter Health IS, Sacramento, CA
 - o ECMC (formerly EdFund Guarantee), Rancho Cordova, CA
- Personal Projects and Client Work
 - Personal Home Page
 - Norcal Noise Fest
 - Musiclandria
 - Berkeley Finnish Hall
 - <u>City Lights Theater Cellista's Finding San Jose (3/24/2021)</u>
- Education & Certification
- Curriculum Vitae
 - Background
 - Summary of Qualifications
 - Selected Project Experience
 - Healthcare Provider
 - Nationwide Student Loan Company

Andrew W Surber

Creative problem solver with 15+ years experience in professional IT environments. Multiple skillset background with focal points on Identity Access Management (IAM), Privileged Access Management (PAM), Automation (Python, Powershell) and Event Management. Seeking opportunities to utilize technology to find solutions for existing and future challenges.

Contacts

PO Box 160601, Sacramento, CA 95816

<u>LinkedIn</u> [https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-w-surber/]

GitHub [https://github.com/awbored]

Summary of Qualifications

- 5+ years working in Sailpoint Identity IQ (IAM) & CyberArk (PAM)
- 7+ years working in Active Directory (LDAP)
- 2 years working in Ansible Automation (Why repeat tasks when we can automate)
- Maintained quick turnaround of projects and tasks

Technical Skills

Platforms

- Windows
- Unix/Linux
- Mac OS X

Languages

- Powershell
- Python
- Bash
- HTML
- CSS
- YAML
- RST

Databases

• MS SQL server

Software

- Red Hat Ansible
- Red Hat Ansible Tower
- Splunk
- Citrix VMware
- Citrix vROPS
- SailPoint IdentityIQ
- CyberArk
- Microsoft Active Directory
- Microsoft O365

- Microsoft Outlook
- Microsoft SCOM
- TOMCAT

Concepts

- GitHub, Version Control
- OOD, Object Oriented Design
- RBAC, Role Based Access Control
- IAM, Identity Access Management
- PAM, Privileged Access Management
- AD and LDAP, Directory Access Protocols
- Automation

Professional Experience

Sutter Health IS, Sacramento, CA

[https://www.sutterhealth.org/]

- System Engineer 2, 07/28/2019-04/2/2021
 - Engineering, implementation, operation, maintenance, and support of a wide range of server platforms including:
 - Microsoft SCOM For Monitoring Microsoft systems
 - Splunk Log ingestion & Searching
 - Red Hat Ansible Automation
 - Infoblox IP Control
 - VMware vROPs vRealize Operations
 - Provided daily, weekly, and monthly systems capacity and performance review metrics for leadership
 - Deployed and retired Windows or RHEL virtual machines over VMware vSphere
 - Created timely event specific automation triggers in Splunk or SCOM for system monitoring and ticket generation
 - Accomplishments:
 - Managed Citrix vROPS (vRealize Operations Manager) Systemwide upgrade to 8.1.1 (10/2020)
 - Managed documentation and user access control to Red Hat Ansible Tower (2/2021)

• Information Security Analyst 3, 04/08/2018-07/28/2019

- Managed IAM, Identity Access Management through SailPoint IdentityIQ
- Managed PAM, Privileged Access Management and password rotation through CyberArk software
- Provided data security support and guidance to Sutter Health regions and affiliates

- Represented the Data Security Office on project teams and other IS initiatives and works with other IS operations support departments to identify and recommend solutions on securityrelated issues
- Provided hands-on security administration of a broad range of security duties
- Provided oversight of design, engineering, analysis, research, testing and monitoring
- Provided regular reporting of security related issues, mostly auditing users with Privileged Access

• Accomplishments:

- Implemented a Server Security Design Standard to ensure server builds met Privileged Access standards
- Provided security insight and created processes for employee onboarding and off boarding
- Lead team and built processes for Server access cleanup project to remove access from servers where privileged access was granted in error

Account Administrator 2, 10/13/2014-04/08/2018

- Managed IAM, Identity Access Management through SailPoint IdentityIQ
- Managed PAM, Privileged Access Management and password rotation through CyberArk software
- Assisted in technical analysis, design, support, and implementation of the day to day account administration requests regarding various types of access and application usage
- Provisioned access for Active Directory, AIX, AS400, UNIX, Linux, Remote Access and related systems
- Assisted in the implementation and support of technical solutions
- Worked with regional and project team members to define business and user requirements
- Removed access from terminated employees
- Upheld security policies regarding access related to job roles of employees

- Upheld security policies regarding Active Directory access
- Provisioned and maintained RightFax systems, a service for converting faxes to digital formats
- RightFax server maintenance and support
- Generated Reports regarding Active Directory access, network shares
- Created and maintained documentation for department processes
- Developed work process for new team innovations
- Accomplishments:
 - Was a key role in updating employee onboarding and off boarding processes (2/2017)
 - Redefined and tuned onboarding process for region specific employees
 - Maintained and updated documentation for team processes and applications
 - Designed and updated RightFax processes for system-wide implementation

Service Desk Representative, 10/21/2013-10/11/2014

- Provided technical support to over 60,000 employees including Doctors, Sutter Health employees, and external vendors through voice and written communications
- Supported Medical systems built on AS/400 platforms
- Handled ticket routing through Remedy software
- Rebuild and correct issues with Outlook profiles including group mailboxes and archive files
- Provided hardware support to HP and Ricoh printers and Fujitsu scanners
- Exceptional customer service skills working in a face paced environment

ECMC (formerly EdFund Guarantee), Rancho Cordova, CA [https://www.ecmc.org/]

• Help Desk Support, 06/2005-01/2013

- Provided technical support to employees, lenders, schools and students through voice and written communications
- Added, removed and maintained users on Active Directory and Linux
- Basic updates to Microsoft Exchange email accounts
- Addressed technical issues from disgruntled users
- Reset access passwords for network systems, upholding security policies
- Troubleshot technical issues determining causes of hardware and software issues
- Configured software remotely
- Created procedures detailing how to resolve issues with clear steps
- Created macros to handle tedious tasks

Personal Projects and Client Work

Personal Home Page [https://andrewway.net/]

Personal blog will detail ongoing events and projects

Norcal Noise Fest

[https://www.youtube.com/norcalnoisefest]

- Primary Sound Engineer for In-Person events
 - Sound board
 - Stage management
 - Sound design
 - Speaker configuration
 - Professional experience working with multiple musicians and performers to deliver amazing audio and performances for the audience
- Technical Wizard For Virtual Events
 - Event streaming over YouTube
 - Video editing
 - Automation scripting for video organizing
 - Video curation
 - Playlist generating
 - Graphic design
 - Capturing video and audio from multiple artists and performers from over the world for live stream during events
 - Experience with multiple streaming software, OBS
 - Experience with VoiP solutions, ZOOM, Discord

Musiclandria [https://www.musiclandria.com/]

- Volunteer for Virtual Events
 - Event streaming over YouTube and Facebook

- Experience with multiple streaming software, OBS and Wirecast
- Sound recording
- Sound design

Berkeley Finnish Hall

[https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdl8zZP472lo4tKM4P6d meQ]

- Technical Lead For Virtual Events
 - Event streaming over YouTube
 - Experience with multiple streaming software, OBS
 - Sound recording
 - Sound design
 - Sound engineer

<u>City Lights Theater - Cellista's Finding San Jose</u> (3/24/2021) [https://www.youtube.com/watch? v=Vl1Sgstf8dA]

- Technical Lead For Virtual Events
 - Event streaming over Facebook, archived to YouTube
 - Experience with multiple streaming software, OBS
 - Directed interviews remotely and captured video for stream
 - Graphic design

Education & Certification

- Company: Red Hat
 - Certification: Automation with Ansible and Ansible Tower (DO410)
 - Completed: December 16, 2019
- Company: Splunk
 - Certification: Splunk 7.x Fundamentals Part 1 (eLearning)
 - o Completed: December 26, 2019
- Company: Sailpoint Technologies
 - Certification: IdentityIQ Implementation: Essentials v7.2
 - Completed: April 19, 2019
- School: Tech Skills of California
 - Certification: Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS)
 - 70-680 Windows 7 Configuration
 - Completed: October 18, 2011
- ITIL V3 Foundation Course
 - ITIL Training Zone 2011

Curriculum Vitae

Background

Andrew is a member of Accenture's Digital Identity practice.

Andrew is a creative problem solver with 15+ years experience in professional IT environments. Multiple skillset background with focal points on Identity Access Management (IAM), Privileged Access Management (PAM), Automation (Python, Powershell) and Event Management. Seeking opportunities to utilize technology to find solutions for existing and future challenges.

Summary of Qualifications

- 5+ years working in Sailpoint Identity IQ (IAM) & CyberArk (PAM)
- 7+ years working in Active Directory (LDAP)
- 2 years working in Ansible Automation (Why repeat tasks when we can automate)
- Maintained quick turnaround of projects and tasks

Selected Project Experience

Healthcare Provider

- System Engineer
 - Engineering, implementation, operation, maintenance, and support of a wide range of server platforms including:
 - Microsoft SCOM For Monitoring Microsoft systems
 - Splunk Log ingestion & Searching
 - Red Hat Ansible Automation
 - Infoblox IP Control

- VMware vROPs vRealize Operations
- Provided daily, weekly, and monthly systems capacity and performance review metrics for leadership
- Deployed and retired Windows or RHEL virtual machines over VMware vSphere
- Created timely event specific automation triggers in Splunk or SCOM for system monitoring and ticket generation

• Accomplishments:

- Managed Citrix vROPS (vRealize Operations Manager) Systemwide upgrade to 8.1.1 (10/2020)
- Managed documentation and user access control to Red Hat Ansible Tower (2/2021)

• Information Security Analyst

- Managed IAM, Identity Access Management through SailPoint IdentityIQ
- Managed PAM, Privileged Access Management and password rotation through CyberArk software
- Provided data security support and guidance to Sutter Health regions and affiliates
- Represented the Data Security Office on project teams and other IS initiatives and works with other IS operations support departments to identify and recommend solutions on securityrelated issues
- Provided hands-on security administration of a broad range of security duties
- Provided oversight of design, engineering, analysis, research, testing and monitoring
- Provided regular reporting of security related issues, mostly auditing users with Privileged Access

• Accomplishments:

- Implemented a Server Security Design Standard to ensure server builds met Privileged Access standards
- Provided security insight and created processes for employee onboarding and off boarding
- Lead team and built processes for Server access cleanup project to remove access from servers where

privileged access was granted in error

• Account Administrator

- Managed IAM, Identity Access Management through SailPoint IdentityIQ
- Managed PAM, Privileged Access Management and password rotation through CyberArk software
- Assisted in technical analysis, design, support, and implementation of the day to day account administration requests regarding various types of access and application usage
- Provisioned access for Active Directory, AIX, AS400, UNIX, Linux, Remote Access and related systems
- Assisted in the implementation and support of technical solutions
- Worked with regional and project team members to define business and user requirements
- Removed access from terminated employees
- Upheld security policies regarding access related to job roles of employees
- Upheld security policies regarding Active Directory access
- Provisioned and maintained RightFax systems, a service for converting faxes to digital formats
- RightFax server maintenance and support
- Generated Reports regarding Active Directory access, network shares
- Created and maintained documentation for department processes
- Developed work process for new team innovations
- Accomplishments:
 - Was a key role in updating employee onboarding and off boarding processes (2/2017)
 - Redefined and tuned onboarding process for region specific employees
 - Maintained and updated documentation for team processes and applications

 Designed and updated RightFax processes for system-wide implementation

• Service Desk Representative

- Provided technical support to over 60,000 employees including Doctors, Sutter Health employees, and external vendors through voice and written communications
- Supported Medical systems built on AS/400 platforms
- Handled ticket routing through Remedy software
- Rebuild and correct issues with Outlook profiles including group mailboxes and archive files
- Provided hardware support to HP and Ricoh printers and Fujitsu scanners
- Exceptional customer service skills working in a face paced environment

Nationwide Student Loan Company

• Help Desk Support

- Provided technical support to employees, lenders, schools and students through voice and written communications
- Added, removed and maintained users on Active Directory and Linux
- Basic updates to Microsoft Exchange email accounts
- Addressed technical issues from disgruntled users
- Reset access passwords for network systems, upholding security policies
- Troubleshot technical issues determining causes of hardware and software issues
- Configured software remotely
- Created procedures detailing how to resolve issues with clear steps
- Created macros to handle tedious tasks

Index